between km and who signed the Minsk
между км и кем подписывались минские
agreements
соглашения
Yanukovych is correct and well, Putin and Putin
Янукович правильно и ну и Путин и Путин
Yes Yanukovych and Putin signed the
Да Янукович и Путин подписали в Минске
Minsk agreements in Minsk that Ukraine is
минские соглашения что Украина
stopping the development of nuclear
что прекращает Ну разработку ядерного
weapons Where are you from We are from Moscow I am from Lithuania
оружия Вы откуда Мы из Москвы Я из Литвы
city kaun us And how do you communicate
город каун нас А чем общаетесь
How again the city  the name of the city is
Как ещё раз город называется город
Kaunas Kaunas Kaunas Wow, we don’t know such people
Каунас Каунас Каунас Ого таких не знаем
Well, this is a Lithuanian
Ну это литовский
city, some of you are students, yes Where did you
город какие-то вы студенты да А откуда
come from Moscow to Moscow, yes No  We’re not
Из Москвы приехали в Москву да Не не мы
locals And this is your hut or dorm, this hut is
местные А это у вас хата или общага хата
like this
такая
Yes, whose is this mine you’re renting or is this
Да а это чья моя вы снимаете или это
your my hut, it’s a bummer and why is it so
ваша моя хата капец а что она такая
dead? Well, this is what the Soviets are left with.
убитая Ну вот такая вот совков осталась
Well, the hut remains. And the repairs. Maybe here,
Ну хата осталась А ремонт Может у нас
if in Lithuania, I’d be in  I lived in a house like this, they
если в Литве Я бы в такой хате жил меня
would laugh at me Yes, well, I’m like that, you sleep
засмеялись бываю Да ну я так ты спишь
there under this wall, it’s
там вот под этой стеной облу тебе
okay for you not the main apartment,
нормально не основная квартира
spare spare, so clean, get drunk here,
запасная запасная так чисто побухать тут
come and hang out. It’s cool at
прийти потусоваться
you are registered there, well, you can
Прикольно у вас вписка там ну можно и
say so, I understood who you are studying to become a
так сказать понял на кого учитесь на
lawyer. It’s cool, I’m also a lawyer. Well, it’s true,
юриста Прикольно я тоже юрист Ну правда
I’m a lawyer in Lithuania. You have a slightly different
я в Литве юрист у вас немножко другое
right, yes, you have the right of the
право да у вас право
strong, whoever is stronger is
сильного кто сильнее тот и
right. You’re in what course, already
прав Ты на каком курсе уже
in the third college I understood Which one?
на третьих колледжа понял А какая
Your specialty is civil law,
Специальность у тебя гражданское право
criminal law, in general, law enforcement,
уголовное вообще правоохранительная
we go through everything at once, both
деятельность мы всё и сразу проходим и
criminal and civil. No, it’s clear. Well,
уголовная и гражданская Не ну ясно Ну
since law enforcement officers, then the
раз правоохранители то специально
specialization will be criminal. Well,
специализация будет уголовная Да
in general, probably, yes, criminal, directly
вообще наверное да уголовная прямо
oriented, but deeply  We also
направленность но глубоко Мы также и
go through civil and administrative cases. It’s cool, listen, how do you
проходим Прикольно слушай Как ты
feel about that, you see that as a
относишься к тому вот смотришь что как
future lawyer, that in Russia they are now giving
юрист будущий что в России сейчас дают
some kind of wildly long sentences to
какие-то такие дикие большие сроки вот
these all sorts of other agents or whoever
этим всяким ина агентам или кто там
said something against their own, more than they
против сво что-то сказал больше чем
give to murderers  the deadlines are
убийцам дают сроки
terrible It’s somehow not always the case there,
ужасно Это как-то вообще случая там не
like he said something
всегда вот типа вот он сказал что-то
against his own, which means he needs a deadline, for
против сво значит ему надо срок
sure he said something else, well,
наверняка он что-то ещ говорил ну вот
that’s not Well, even if something Well, yes, that is, it
это не Ну даже если что Ну да то есть
turns out that the words are  words Yes,
получается что слова за слова Да
some kind of misunderstanding of their army and
какие-то там не восприятия сво армии и
so on Yes, they give more than for
так дальше Да дают больше чем за
premeditated murder Yes, this is terrible, this is
умышленное убийство Да это ужасно такое
often far-fetched But in general this is
часто притянуто за уш Но вообще это
wrong I think yes, I
неправильно Я считаю да
understand And you are some kind of streamer Yes,
понял А вы Стример какой-то Стример Да
from Lithuania the most And stream now  Yes, now
из Литвы самый А стрими сейчас да сейчас
stream from me every evening in Lithuania,
стрими у меня каждый вечер в Литве
it’s interesting, we’ll get somewhere
стримы интересно попадём мы куда-нибудь
Well, if you’re interested, we’ll talk Well,
Ну если интересно поговорим
you know, we’re not propagandists And who’s
Ну мы так знаете не пропагандисты А кто
whose Crimea Russia means a propagandist no
чей Крым Россия значит пропагандист нет
But a propagandist  You can call anyone
А пропагандистом можно назвать любого
at all No, you can’t call me a
вообще нет меня не назовёшь
propagandist What does the word mean? Well, you
пропагандистом А что значит слово Ну вы
ask such provocative questions Yes,
такие провокационные вопросы задаёте Да
I’m a provocateur, that’s you
я провокатор это ты
right. What does the word propagandist mean?
правильно А что значит слово
dissemination of
пропаганда - это распространение
information is good, so you have
информации хорошо вот у вас есть
an audience, let’s say you are broadcasting something to them, that
аудитория допустим вы что-то на неё
means no, I’m not No, look,
вещает значит это нет я не Нет смотрите
you’re a little confused I understand, I’m not
Вы немножко не Поня я не
distributing, I’m a propagandist, I’m  I
распространяют я я пропагандист я
’m provoking, you’re a propagandist because you’re
провоцирую ты пропагандист потому что ты
saying that Crimea is Russian,
вот говоришь что Крым - это российский
this is Russian Propaganda And I’m a provocateur,
это Российская Пропаганда А я провокатор
I’m provoking people to think, turn on their brains Yeah,
я провоцирую людей думать включать мозг
to say this, not not to
Ага на то чтобы это сказать да не не на
say this, to come,
то чтобы это сказать на то чтобы Прити
let’s try a session provocateur
вот Давайте попробуем сеанс провокатор
Swa want  that’s interesting. Wait, but
Сва хотите вот интересно Подожди А вот
if I said that Crimea was Ukrainian, then
если бы я сказал что Крым украинский то
who would I be? Well, you weren’t a
кто бы я был ну ты не был пока
propagandist yet, but I would carry out a further
пропагандистом но я бы дальше провёл
test No  I would be a propagandist
тест Нет я бы был пропагандистом потому
because I would say that And why And how does it
что я бы сказал что А почему А как это
depend? Because you really said
зависит Потому что ты сказал реально
the truth, that’s if you say Look,
правду это вот е если ты говоришь Смотри
the earth is round, You’re not a propagandist, well, in a
земля круглая Ты же не пропагандист ну в
certain sense, I’m carrying information,
определённом смысле я же несу информацию
they’re listening,
это слушают
no, that’s what The person who  says
нет вот че Человек который говорит
look, the snow is white, this is not
смотрите снег белый Это же не
Propaganda. Well, if I’m
Пропаганда Ну если я это
agitating for this, I’ll convey this, if you have
агитируют я это доношу если у тебя есть
an audience, this is Propaganda,
публика это Пропаганда можно при То есть
if you shout from the balcony, people are
если если вы с балкона крикнули народ
snowing white, then you  propagandist Well, it
снег белый то вы пропагандист Ну
turns out in its own way Yes, I understand, yes,
получается в своём роде Да понял да
let’s, I’m interested because I’m a
давайте Вот мне интересно потому что я
professional provocateur Let’s
профессиональный провокатор Давайте
try, I’m provoking you, a
попробуем вот я вас по провоцирую
professional provocateur
профессиональный провокатор
Yes, so interesting, I have 18 years of practice,
Да так интересно у меня 18 лет практики
in 2 years it will be the twentieth I’m
через 2 года будет двадцатой Я вот вас
provoking you, I’m provoking people to
по провоцирую я провоцирую людей
think, I’m turning on  their cognitive
размышлять включаю когнитивные ихние
abilities and activating their gray
способности и активизируя их серое
matter, here’s a question for you: why do you
вещество вот вопрос к вам да почему вы
think that Crimea is Russia? You, well,
считаете что Крым - это Россия вы Ну мы
we, you think that Krom  this is Ukraine, I
мы ты считаешь что Кром это украи я ни
didn’t say a word. Well, okay, yes, give
слова не сказал Ну хорошо Да давай ко
me a question because they were carried out and
мне вопрос потому что проводились нду и
geographically Crimea is the territory of the
географически Крым является территорией
Russian Federation. What does it mean geographically? Well, there are
РФ Что значит географически Ну там
borders for citizens there. Well, a
границ проходит там граждан Ну
Russian passport, a Russian passport, Well,
российский паспорт российский паспорт Ну
yes No, look at the passport. For example,
да Нет смотрите паспорт Например у
many residents of Germany also have  a
многих жителей Германии тоже есть
Russian passport and a person with a
российский паспорт а человек с
Russian stop stop stop So wait, you
российский стоп стоп стоп Так подожди Ты
leaked, you said that he didn’t answer, he is
же слился ты же сказал что не отвеча он
now defending
сейчас защищает
He is defending this thesis Yes, look,
Он защищает этот тезис Да смотри наличие
people have Passports, this is not For example, in
Паспорта у людей это не Вот например на
Cyprus now  There are a lot of people with a Russian
Кипре сейчас людей с российским
passport. Yes, that doesn’t make
паспортом Овер дофига Да это не делает
it
это
the territory of citizenship, that’s all, but
территорию гражданства это всё да
citizenship of citizens is a relationship with
гражданство граждане - это соотношение с
states and not with territory, he can
государствам а не с территорией он может
live anywhere. Yes, for example, a person with
жить где угодно Да например человек с
Russian citizenship can live in
российским гражданством может жить в
Ukraine, Poland, America. Yes, here’s a
Украине в Польше в Америке Да вот
referendum refrain
референдум рефрен
ry is not recognized by the world community nor by
ры не признан мировым сообществом ни
Ukraine under any
Украиной ни по какому он
legislation it was carried out it
законодательству проводился он
was carried out when Russian
проводился когда пришли российские
troops arrived Yes and they made a fake referendum
войска Да и сделали фейковый референдум
just like in  In Kherson, in Kherson,
также как в Херсоне в Херсоне тоже
troops also came and made a referendum, you
пришли войска и сделали референдум ты
say that Kherson is
ска что Херсон - это
Russia Where is Kherson, Kherson
Россия Где находится Херсон херсонс
region
область
Yes, near Smolensk, so he knows, between
Да возле Смоленска так его знает между
Smolensk and Bryansk, Kherson is located And I
Смоленском и Брянском Херсон находится А
understood everything In short,
всё понял Короче
between you know where it is to the left of Moscow Well, they
между знаешь где смо слева от Москвы Ну
border on Belarus just a little  - a little
граничат с беларусью вот чуть-чуть
lower, look, Russia captured
ниже да то смотри Россия захватила
Kherson, held a referendum there and included
Херсон провела там референдум и вписала
it in its Constitution, just like Crimea later
её в свою Конституцию как и Крым потом
Ukraine recaptured, made a breakthrough between
Украина отбила сделала рывок между
Smolensk and Bryansk and recaptured Kherson,
Смоленском и Брянском и отбила Херсон
expelled Russia from Kherson, and in the Russian
выгнала из Херсона Россию А в Российской
Constitution the written word Kherson remained, then
Конституции остался записанный Херсон то
Kherson is now Is it Russia or Ukraine Well,
Херсон сейчас Это Россия или Украина Ну
in translation of the war, I think, well, it makes no
в перевод войны я думаю ну не имеет
sense to talk about this, you can’t understand
смысла о таком рассуждать нельзя понять
Whose territory is because there is a War  no,
Чья территория потому что идёт Война нет
look why and when, for example,
так смотрите почему и когда например
Hitler captured part of the USSR Yes, uh,
Гитлер захватил часть СССР Да вот ээ
Hitler’s troops were in Crimea. Well, what’s
гитлеровские войска были в Крыму Ну что
this about the USSR saying that this is territory
тут это СССР говорит что это территория
occupied?  Hitler, this is the territory
захваченная Гитлером это те территория
No, this is not controversial, no one argued, this is
Нет это не спорно никто не спорил это
the territory of the Soviet Union. The Soviet
территория Советского Союза Советский
Union believed that no one argued, but the war
Союз считал никто не спорил но война то
ended well. Well, they repulsed like these
как закончилась Ну отбили типа этих
Germans and everything seems to me during the war, it’s
немцев и всё мне кажется в период войны
better not to talk about it. No, that’s exactly what they
об этом лучше не сто Нет как раз и
say  and they say, look, we
говорят как раз и говорят смотри мы
see that also Ukraine Yes, now
видим Что также Украина Да сейчас
Ukraine has captured part of Kursk. The fact is
Украина захватила часть курско Дело в
that they wanted to make another
том что они хотели ещё один сделать
push towards Kherson through Bryansk, they
рывок удар на Херсон ещё через Брянск
wanted to do it, and they captured part of the
хотели сделать да и захватили часть
Kursk region along the road. So Russia is
Курской области по дороге Вот и Россия
still  didn’t recapture, then it turns out
до сих пор не отвоевала то получается
part of the Kursk region is Ukraine Well, it
часть Курской области - это Украина Ну
turns out I understand, that is, it turns out Whose
получается понял то есть получается Чьи
troops are standing in both that and the territory yes Well,
войска стоят то и та и территория да Ну
yes, I’m thinking ahead That is, if
да я думаю вперёд То есть если если
tomorrow, besides uh In addition to this, in addition to
завтра кроме ээ Кроме этого кроме
Kherson, Ukraine also recaptures Smolensk and
Херсона Украина отвоюю ещё Смоленск и
Bryansk, then you will  say that
Брянск то вы будете говорить Что
Smolensk is Ukraine,
Смоленск - это Украина
well, in fact, Yes, it seems to me that ahead of the war,
ну по факту Да мне кажется вперёд войны
territories are divided like this, well, look, I’ll
так и делятся территории ну смотрите я
tell you a secret. Smolensk is
вам раскрою секрет Смоленск - это
Belarus, these are historical Belarusian
Беларусь это исторические белорусские
lands Yes  temporarily
земли Да захваченные Россией временно
occupied territory of Belarus seized by Russia Uh-
оккупированная территория Беларуси Угу
huh Okay with Crimea sorted out But
О'кей с Крымом разобрались А вот
look, what do you think about this war,
смотрите Как вы считаете вот эта война
which has been going on since 1914
которая идёт уже э с четырнадцатого года
and has been going on since the 2nd year? In general,
а с 2 второго идёт Вообще
people in the Russian Federation are fed up with a full-scale one,
полномасштабного людей в Российской
of course. Did you think that this could be the
конечно А вы думали что может быть такая
situation?  that students will also be
ситуация что студентов тоже начнут
taken to war, they will say that there are not enough
забирать на войну скажут что не хватает
soldiers against NATO Yes,
воинов против НАТО Да
of course you are not afraid
конечно Вы не боитесь
no
нет
yes
да
Well why aren’t you
Ну а почему ты не
afraid Well because  I probably understand
боишься Ну потому что наверно понимаю
that the
что и обстоятельства
circumstances of the state are such. The
обстоятельства в государства такой
event horizon needs to be
Горизонт событий его надо как-то
fulfilled somehow. You would like to die in
выполнять тебе хотелось бы умереть в
Ukraine, no, but in the Kherson region. No,
Украине нет а в Херсонской области Нет
I would not like to die. And in Smolensk, I
мне не хотелось бы умирать А в Смоленске
understand. And you would like to be
так понял А ты хотел бы чтобы тебя
taken to the war against
забрали на войну против
Ukraine
Украины
No, you want Russia and
Нет ты хочешь чтобы росия с
Ukraine. I am against the very fact of the
Украиной Я против самого факта
war. But I think that what is happening
войны Но я считаю что то что происходит
now is more of a necessary measure. I understand
сейчас Это скорее вынужденная мера понял
how you think
как ты считаешь ээ для России важны
the lives of its
жизни своих
people are important for Russia. Well, just like for any state.
людей Ну да как и для любого государства
Okay, if they are important, it is important.  future question:
Окей если важны важно будущее вопрос как
What do you think? Maybe it would be better for Russia to
Как ты считаешь Может лучше чтобы Россия
give Crimea back to Ukraine Donetsk Lugansk
отдала Украине назад Крым Донецк Луганск
and leave the territory of Ukraine so as not to
и вышла с территории Украины чтобы не
kill its Russian citizens. Listen,
убивать своих граждан российских Слушай
maybe it’s better that Ukraine will surrender and Ukraine is
а может лучше Украина сдастся а Украина
not Ukraine, a puppet of America, that’s all,
не Украина марионетка Америки всё
America won’t let Ukraine surrender, that’s all,
Америка не даст Украине сдаться всё тут
I’m just from  Look, I also thought,
просто я из я смотри я тоже думал да
let the Ukrainians surrender, they say everything,
пусть украинцы сдадутся они говорят всё
America won’t give everything, America won’t give everything,
Америка не даст всё Америка не даст
so it turns out that America, look,
поэтому получается что Америка смотри
America will fight to the last
Америка будет воевать до последнего
Russian, so this is the question for Russia
русского так вот вопрос для России
Russia is a huge country Why should she uh
Россия огромнейшая страна Для чего Ей ээ
do that millions of Russians die for the
делать чтобы погибали миллионы россиян
sake of some new piece of territory
ради какого-то нового кусочка территории
because they will step on the Adam’s apple now we
потому что наступят на кадык сейчас
won’t fight back
дальше не отобьёмся
on which Adam’s apple you’ve already stepped on a nut on
на какой кадык вам уже на орешку на
the nuts with a sausage you’ve already had your
орешки наступили с колбаской вам уже
nuts pressed  So your hazel tree is
орешки прижали Так что ваш орешник
already cracking like Listen, well, look, well,
трещит уже как Слушай ну как смотри ну
really, if you’re watching, if you can’t, the
реально если вы смотрите если вы не може
Americans are not like they came in  in the Kursk region, the Americans are firing their missiles at Russian territory I officially declare for now atam Well, that’s all and Russia can’t do anything America won’t even launch a drone on Poland Well listen Time will tell So time has already seemed like history is being written by the winners Look at when I in the twenty-second year I communicated with the Russians Yes, they told me Time will tell in the twenty-third So time shows that the Russians have since been expelled from the Kyiv region from Kherson from the Kharkov region from the Kursk region from  in the
американцы Да не то что вошли в курскую
Kursk region, can you imagine Stalin,
курско области это представляешь Сталин
if he heard this, he would
бы если бы это услышал в гробу бы
turn over in his grave; they themselves gave away
перевернулся сами отдавали
strategically German tanks in the Kursk
стратегически немецкие танки в Курской
region again, Stalin is just
области снова Сталин просто в гробу
rolling over in his grave, you know, your grandfathers fought so that
переворачивается понимаешь деды воевали
German NATO tanks would not be in the
чтобы немецкие натовские танки не были в
Kursk region with their
Курской области своими
bodies. And what do you
телами А у вас и что
get instead?  so now to
получается вместо того чтобы теперь
say, in short, okay, all the lives of Russians
сказать Короче ладно всё жизни россиян
come first, let’s not
превыше всего давайте мы не будем
fight for this territory, we’ll give it
воевать за эту территорию отдаём Украине
back to Ukraine. This is Crimea, Donetsk  Lugansk
назад Вот это Крым Донецк Луганск
Kherson region Zaporozhye Kursk
херсонскую область запорожскую курскую
Bryansk our labors will also go in vain
брянскую наши труды тоже пойдут впустую
and here people will not agree What does
а тут уже люди не согласны будут Что
T mean first of all What does it mean that
значит Т во-первых Что значит труды у
your labors are not labors you have the deaths of your people and
вас не труды у вас смерти ваших людей и
what does it mean that people do not agree you in Russia
что значит люди не согласны ты в Росси
stop stop stop in  Russia, wait, people
подо стоп стоп стоп в Росси подожди люди
don’t agree. Do you really think that
не согласны Ты реально считаешь что на
someone in Russia cares about people’s opinions?
мнение людей кому-то в России не всё
What will people do? At the rally,
равно А что люди сделают На митинг вы
imagine tomorrow, and Putin or
вот Представь завтра да Путин или тот
whoever will be there now  Putin Yes, he will say
кто сейчас будет после Путина Да скажет
Everything, we are withdrawing troops from Ukraine, we are giving
Всё мы выводим войска из Украины отдаём
back these territories to them, together with the Kursk
назад им эти территории вместе с Курской
region, you will come to the rally Well, people will
областью ты выйдешь На митинг Ну люди
come out anyway Who will attend which rally is the
по-любому выйдут Кто на какой митинг
opposition Well, there will be a second Maidan only
оппозиция Ну будет второй Майдан только
for what kind of opposition who is some kind of opposition in
на какая какая оппозиция кто оппозиция в
Russia  will begin What kind of
России какая-нибудь то начнётся Какая
opposition will a
оппозиция кто
crowd of dissatisfied people come out? What
выйдет толпа недовольных людей Какая
look Strelkov look heroes liberals
смотри Стрелкова смотри герои либералы
in general that liberals will come out against
вообще что либералы выйдут против того
ending the war liberals will do the opposite
чтобы войну закончили либералам наоборот
it’s good against giving away some
хорошо против того что отдавать какую-то
part of yours who will come out well who Name
часть своего кто выйдет ну кто Назови
this liberal this is who Which politician
этого либерала вот кто Кто из политиков
will come out against who this is the party that
выйдет против кто вот партия которая
was after
была после
Navalny Which As an
Навального Какая Как
option Well, there was a party of his from Navalny
вариант Ну вот от Навального же его была
that remained after him this
партия какая-то осталась После него эта
party  only now he doesn’t lead it,
партия только он теперь ей не руководит
they will be a lot anyway, in principle, I
они по-любому будут в принципе много я
think Russia, wait, I understood
думаю Россия подожди я правильно понял
this joke correctly that if Putin withdraws
этот анекдот что если Путин выведет
troops from Ukraine, then
войска из Украины да то Соратники
Navalny’s associates will go out to protests, yes,
Навального выйдут на протесты да
interesting
интересная
sophistry I haven’t heard of this yet
софистика такого я ещ не
Yulia Navalny Bring back the wings this is
слышал Юлия Навального Верните кры это
not
не
a sandwich Ilya no Well look I’ll say this in
бутербро Илья не Ну смотри я скажу так в
Russia no one will come out if tomorrow Yes
России никто не выйдет если завтра Да
just like look the Soviet Union withdrew
также как смотри Советский Союз вывел
troops from Afghanistan someone came out
войска из Афганистана кто-то вышел
against this everyone sighed UPO The Union
против этого все вздохнули упо Союз
withdrew troops from  In East Germany,
вывел войска из Восточной Германии
someone came out against everyone, everyone took it and
кто-то вышел против Все взяли и
calmed down, if tomorrow in Russia they say
успокоились если завтра в России скажут
that everything is over, we are withdrawing
что всё сво закончилось мы выводим
troops from Ukraine, we are giving them everything back,
войска из Украины отдаём им всё назад
everyone will take a short breath and will  continue to work for yourself Well, in the same way now in Moscow, it’s as if everyone is working. Even during the war, it’s not like that, look at it now, in short, and sanctions and everything, and he understands, and people are dying, people are dying, and there is no end to this and the edge of understanding America will not retreat before, we also thought there in They showed us in Lithuania. What did we think, that now, in short, Russia will attack Ukraine and that’s it, and Ukraine will surrender, yes. And that’s all if when Russia was knocked out from near Kyiv, then it became clear that everything if Russia needs to capture Kyiv in order to defeat Ukraine
Все вздохнут короче и будут дальше себе
if Russia fled from Kyiv and everything even Belarus won’t give up its territory for an attack on Ukraine, they won’t take Kiev. And without this, it’s eternal death from American weapons of Russian soldiers, that’s all. Therefore, if tomorrow Putin says there or someone will take his place, so what? We are withdrawing troops and it’s over, no one will come out, you won’t come out, you won’t come out, you don’t need it, no one needs a day, what kind of rally if people didn’t come out for raising the retirement age, if people didn’t come out there for anything at all  why, when do you even
за вообще ни за что когда ты вообще
remember that the last time people went
помнишь что последний раз люди выходили
to a rally in
на митинг в
Moscow, you know the word rally in our
Москве знаете оние слово митинг в нашем
jurisprudence, it’s like yours, I don’t know.
правоведении это как у вас это не знаю А
Well, say a rally, that is, some kind of
ну скажи митинг то есть какое-то
event, without weapons, peacefully. People
мероприятие Без оружия мирно Люди
go out to the square to gather for something...  then they
выходят на площадь собираются за что-то
perform Well, our people usually speak out,
выступают Ну люди у нас обычно выступают
not peacefully, as I know at various
как бы ну не мирно как я знаю на разных
rallies. And how do they speak out,
митингах А как они выступают как
like now in
например сейчас в
Georgia, wait, do you really want to say
Грузии подожди Ты реально хочешь сказать
that someone will come out and throw
что кто-то выйдет и будет кидать в
cocktails at the police in Russia
полицейских в России коктейлями
Molotov I said about Molotov cocktails,
Молотова Я сказал про коктейли Молотова
well, how would it be not to hold a peaceful
ну как как будет не мирно
rally? Well, you have aggressive people, you have people who are
митинговать Ну агрессив у вас у вас люди
even afraid to hold a peaceful rally, what kind of
даже мирно боятся митинговать про какую
aggression are you talking about? Well, this is not only in
агрессию ты говоришь Ну это не только у
our country, in many countries where there is a very tough
нас во многих странах где очень жёсткая
conservative government, such
власть консервативная такая
people Mitin, then and there, I  I’m saying what kind of
люди Митин то то Я же говорю то какие
rallies if now the Dictator says
митинги если вот сейчас Диктатор скажет
everything, we started the war, no one came out, We
на Всё мы начали войну никто не вышел Мы
ended the war, and no one will
закончили войну также никто не
come out. It’s just that you think more soberly, it’s
выйдет Просто ты более трезво мыслишь
just your colleague of some kind  fairy tales
просто твой коллега какой-то сказки
are told by people who will go to rallies,
рассказывают люди на митинги выйдут на
what
какие
rallies will they go to, unless you know, I’ll blow you off with the police,
митинги разве что знаешь выду с полицие
gentle caresses with a baton, this is what it’s like. But for
нежные ласки с дубинкой это такое А вот
example, I don’t. Well, I agree, the Maidan was worse in
например не Ну согласен Майдан похлеще в
that sense, but it wasn’t the Maidan.
этом смысле был да там вот не Майдан Да
But the Ukrainians, look, I’m from Lithuania, my
вот украинцы я смотри я из Литвы я моё
heart is with  Ukraine today because I
сердце с Украиной сегодня с пому что я
watch how people fight for their rights
смотрю как люди борятся за свои права
and how in Russia and then millions came out to
это и как в России да вышел тогда на
Bolotnaya. They came out and
Болотную миллионы Вышли да и
dispersed in Russia when it comes  100
разошлись в России когда приходит 100
people come alone and disperse
человек приходит один и разгоняет
a demonstration in Ukraine or in Georgia
демонстрацию в Украине или в Грузии
come Yes, one protester comes and
приходит Да приходит один протестующий
disperses them, that’s the
разгоняет их вот
difference in Georgia I saw with water
разница в Грузии видел с водо
such reliable power Yes, well, there’s
такая власть надёжная Да ну водомёта там
a lot of water cannon there, no, I’m not talking like a water cannon,
много что там Не ну говорю как водомёта
since a girl is standing with a flag holding it
раз девушка стоит флаг держит ей это
from behind, they saw it  then the water hits, it
сзади видели тогда вода бьёт она
shows that she washes her hair and
показывает что она как моет голову и
stands like this and like that and it’s right there. It’s
такая и такая стоит и аж прямо это Это
creepy because it shows
пробирает потому что это показывает да
that people are ready to stand up for their ideas,
что люди готовы за свои идеи
no, but we
стоять вране нет но у нас
less conservative, I can’t just
менее консервативны я не могу просто
give a clear answer because I can’t
чётко дать ответ потому что я не могу
imagine that tomorrow Russia will
представить такого что завтра Россия
retreat to me. It’s hard to imagine. Well,
отступит мне Сложно представить Ну
why is the Russian mentality such that
почему вот русский менталитет такой что
yes, we tolerate a lot, but we’ll give in, it
да терпим мы много прям но дамся
will begin you you could you imagine that
начнётся ты ты ты мог представить что
Russia Russia stood near Kiev A  here
Россия Россия стояла под Киевом А тут
she would retreat from
она отступит от
Kiev you could
Киева ты мог
Eh yes you could imagine that Russia
Э да ты мог представить что Россия
would capture Kherson and then leave Kherson she
захватит Херсон а потом уйдёт из Херсона
retreated from the Kharkov region she
отступила из Харьковской области
didn’t even retreat  retreated ran away I’m not
отступила даже не отступила убежала я не
very knowledgeable in war But I know for sure that
сильно сведущ в войне Но точно знаю что
some areas We gave up out of
какие-то области Мы отдавали из
strategic interest Well, yes,
стратегического интереса Ну вот да
withdraw the troops
отвести войска
regrouping you know the move
перегруппировку знаеш ход
regrouping for a century 100 years they
перегруппировка на столетие 100 лет
leave Ukraine so that in 100 years
уходят из Украины чтобы за 100 лет
regrouping so you can
перегруппировка так ты можешь себе
imagine not imagine but  A fact
представлять не представлять но Факт
is a fact, yes, Russia is far from the
есть факт да Россия ээ далеко не
Soviet Union. The Soviet Union lost the
Советский Союз Советский Союз проиграл
arms race with America. Yes, and it
гонку вооружений с Америкой Да и
collapsed. The Soviet Union controlled
развалился Советский Союз контролировал
damn half of Europe and half of Africa.  half of Asia
блин пол Европы Да пол Африки пол Азии
has collapsed now Russia doesn’t have
развалился теперь Россия не имеет
as many people as it had the Soviet
Столько людей сколько имел Советский
Union doesn’t have as much technology doesn’t have
Союз не имеет столько техники не имеет
as much industry it’s a pitiful
столько промышленности это жалкая
breed of the Soviet Union
породия Советского Союза
everything is a complete successor So what’s the difference I’m
всё приёмник полный Так какая разница Я
talking about the complete military economic plan of the
же говорю про Военно экономический план
Soviet Union in general anyway a
полный Советского Союза вообще всё равно
successor is not a successor like I’m saying  that
преемник не преемник типа говорю что
Russia has the potential to butt heads with
Россия у неё есть потенциал бодаться с
America No, it’s not even a second-
Америкой Нет она даже не страна второго
tier country, so it has resources. Well, what kind of
эшелона так вот есть ресурсы Ну Какие
resources do we use these resources quite
ресурсы эти ресурсы мы довольно
illiterately? No, look at the resources
неграмотно используем нет смотри ресурсы
in the modern world; resources are not just, for
в современном мире ресурсы это не просто
example, dug up  coal dug up iron and
например выкопал уголь выкопал железо и
so on Yes, in the modern world it’s what
так дальше Да в современном мире это что
you make from these resources Yes, if you
ты делаешь из этих ресурсов Да если ты
produce nothing but a shovel, what about
ничего кроме лопаты производст что про
domestic production, what Russia
отечественное производство что Россия
can produce, export yes Yes,
может производить экспортировать да Да
the fact is that look Russia cannot
дело в том что смотри Россия не может
produce, it does not compete with the West
выпуска она не конкурирует с западом
at all  not in the World Cup in computer technology,
вообще ни в ЧМ в компьютерной технике
because we have a
пото что у нас пория
semi-final, in my opinion, when we buy
полуфинал по-моему такы когда закупаем
some computers from China, we install a couple of
из Китая какие-нибудь компы ставим пару
diodes and here you are, Russian-
диодов и вот тебе Российская
made, but to me, well, that’s bad, yes
производство но мне Ну это плохо да
because it’s much more profitable than
потому что это гораздо выгоднее чем заво
spending a lot of money on ambassadors for 10 years
10 лет убивать на это послов кучу денег
and expecting that someday in the future it will
и ожидать что когда-нибудь в будущем это
pay off. Well, within the framework of real
окупится ну в рамках настоящего
capitalism, this is the only
капитализма это единственный вариант
economic option for Russia for now,
экономики для России пока
that is,
что то есть
look, you agree that Russia simply
смотри ты согласен что Россия просто не
cannot compete with  develop even with
может конкурировать с разви даже с одной
America alone cannot, let alone with the soya bloc of
Америкой не может не то что с блоком сою
nuclear powers the more powerful economies of the world
ядерных держав мощней экономиками мира
production Listen, we have a
производст Слушай у нас
processor Oh my God with this process
процессор Боже мой с этим процессом
Elbrus you will tell me about
Эльбрус вы мне с д вго года расскажете
the processor
процессор
russian  was manufactured in Taiwan and
рус изготавливался на Тайване и с д
nothing has been produced since the second year,
второго года ничего не изготавливается
look, they stopped selling it Yes, they
посмотри приостановили его продали Да
didn’t sell anything, it’s just that Taiwan said
ничего не продали просто Тайвань сказал
sanctions and in short, we won’t do any more for you,
санкции всё и короче не будем вам дальше
first of all, it’s the dawn
делать во-первых проб это заре
of the architecture of the eighties and nineties,
по архитектуре восьмидесятых девяностых
it’s just like a washing
годов это просто она как стиральная
machine processor, here  and even then it was even
машинка процессор вот а и то его даже
closed. Look in the news, a colleague
закрыли Посмотри в новости вот коллега
will look at how many Elbrus were released
посмотрит Сколько эльбрусом выпустили в
last year in there Zero here on Google
прошлом году в там Ноль вот на Гугле
Now just for fun  I wasn’t a big
Сейчас ради интереса чтобы я не был бало
boy, I’m also now with It’s just that you are not the
болом я тоже сейчас с Просто вы не
first for this Elbrus, you
первые за этот Эльбрус вы где-то
read somewhere, they told you not
начитались вам рассказали не
the eighties of the 2000s, but yes, but the
восьмидесятых нулевых а так да но
potential, that is, look,
потенциал то есть вот смотри
So
Так
now I’m right behind Elbrus, the
сейчас я прямо за Эльбрус вот компания
TSC company has stopped production and supply of
тсц прекратила производство и поставки
products to  Russia yes This means that the
продукции в России да Это означает что
production of Russian
полностью остановлен выпуск российских
processors Baikal and Elbrus has been completely stopped in the
процессоров Байкал и Эльбрус это ещё за
twenty-second year, that’s all
двадцать второй год вот всё
Wikipedia also ebs 8S in connection with the light
Википедии тоже эбс 8S в связи о свет
came to us yes In connection with  sanctions of
появился у нас да В связи с санкциями
some countries for the invasion of Ukraine
некоторых стран за вторжение на Украину
suspended the process of
приостановила проце
these El
всё нет этих Эль
Brus since 2020, the
брусов с 2020
company since 2020, since March, the
компания с 2020 года с марта процессоры
Baikal and Elbrus processors were produced by the Taiwanese
Байкал и Эльбрус выпускала тайваньская
company TM
компания TM
tcmc
tcmc
tsmc in 2022, ready-made batches of these
tsmc в 2022 году готовые партии данных
processors were not released to
процессоров не отпускали в
Russia increasingly more and more simply asked about
Россию всё роче ни просто спросил про
production  fatherland, so look No,
производство отечест так смотри Нет так
in Russia there is no, in Russia there is no
в России нету не в России нету
production of Elbrus, it’s just
производства Эльбруса это просто
bought in Taiwan just like in China
покупалась в Тайване так же как в Китае
Yes, Taiwan disappeared, it was called IBS And that's all And
Да пропало тайвани называлась ИБС И всё
then some kind of architecture And that's all And now
И то архитектура какая-то И всё И теперь
they're not even there
даже Их нету
Well, that's it, that's
Ну вот так
why Russia, instead of
вот так что поэтому Россия вместо того
thinking about how to develop its people Yes
чтобы думать как развивать свой народ Да
How to pull them out of poverty  how to
Как вытянуть его из нищеты как его
bring it into at least some kind of internal
привести в хоть какие-то с внутреняя
economy cannot exist separately
экономика не может существовать отдельно
from the
от
external one instead of thinking How to
внешней вместо того чтобы думать Как
pull your people out of poverty How to give
вытянуть своих людей из нищеты Как дать
them a more developed level Yes, they are thinking about
им более развитый уровень да они думают
how to attack another country and capture
как напасть на другую страну и захватить
more  some piece of
ещё какой-то кусок
territory, look in Russia, how many
территории смотри в России сколько
territories are there to which damn roads can’t
территорий на которые не могут блин
supply
дороги Провести свет газ Ульяновская
electricity?
газ и вот вы молодые парни да вы тоже
this is who you will go to work for and how much
вот кем вы пойдёте работать и сколько
the salary will be this is how much the salary is in
будет зарплата вот сколько зарплата в
the field in which you want to work
той сфере в которой вы хотите работать
Well enough Well enough That’s
Ну достаточно Ну достаточно Это
how much I don’t talk about
сколько принципиально не говорю о
money on principle Well, but my colleague on principle I
деньгах Ну а вот коллега принципиально
don’t talk to anyone Yes  You need it in
ни с кем не говорю у меня Да Вам в
dollars or rubles I'll divide by
долларах или в рублях Я поделю на
110 I can do it in dollars
110 я могу в долларах
Let's say on average I have about 5000
Давай в среднем у меня где-то 5000
5.000 Well, like 500 dollars comes out when
5.000 Ну типа 500 долларов выходит когда
I work there on weekends, that's right,
я работаю там по выходным чисто вот да
500 dollars I believe 5 work, I
500 долларов я верю 5 рабо я по выходным
also work purely on weekends  I have my own business,
чисто работаю также у меня свой бизнес
yes, that is, look, it turns out that an
есть да то есть смотри э получается что
employee who works in Russia, yes,
работник который работает в России да
500 dollars This is his 1,000 dollars
500 долларов Вот это его 1.000 долларов
this is what I work  purely Saturday
это вот я работаю чисто субботу
Sunday what do you work as an animator
воскресенье кем ты работаешь аниматор
like dancing Yes, well there are excursions sometimes Well
типа танцы Да ну там экскурсии иногда Ну
I understand yes yes This is purely passive oh
понял да да Это чисто пассивный ой
passive this is additional income
пассивный это дополнительный заработок
Yes additional income Yes and I think
Да дополнительный заработок Да и я думаю
those who do not work as an animator there
те кто работают не аниматором там
teachers get no more than teachers - This is
учителя получают не больше учителя - Это
a government agency already  that Well,
госструктура уже что и что Ну так так
look, if a teacher in Russia
вот смотри если учитель в России
receives 400 dollars, 500 dollars is the
получает 400 долларов 500 долларов это
ceiling. That is, Russia has oil
потолок Вот то есть и Россия имея нефть
gas gold diamonds, huge resources, but
газ золото алмазы огромнейший ресурсы да
instead of investing in its
вместо того чтобы вкладывать в свою
infrastructure in its teachers in its
инфраструктуру в своих учителей в своих
Doctors in its engineers Yes, in order to
Докторов в своих инженеров Да чтобы
make the lives of its people better, it
делать жизнь своих людей лучше она
spends money to make the lives of people in
тратит деньги чтобы делать жизнь людей в
other countries
других странах
worse. You counted, for example, How much does
хуже Вот вы считали например Сколько
one missile fired at
стоит одна ракета выпущенная по
Ukraine cost? How much could you count, too, a
Украине сколько можно считали тоже
hospital? Well, listen, other countries
больница Ну слушай остальные страны
spend where
тратят куда больше по деньгам на
Look, they spend more money on weapons, yes, in order
вооружение смотри они тратят да Для того
to make defense, to defend Russia. I
чтобы делать оборону защищаться Россия Я
would understand if Russia were attacked. Yes, and
бы понимаю если бы на России напали Да и
she is forced to shoot there, listening to us, who were
она вынуждена там отстреливать слуша мы
taught in the forty-first year. Well, as if we
наученные сорок первым годом Ну как бы и
went to this territory once again  ka in
пошли на эту территорию е раз ска на
Ukraine they are not fascists, once again I don’t know fascists
Украине не фашисты е раз я не знаю фаши
I don’t live in Ukraine but in Ukraine
Я же не живу на Украине но в Украине
there is not so much potential to attack
нету столько потенциала чтобы напасть на
Russia like Hitler, do you imagine
Россию как у Гитлера ты представляешь
Hitler The West doesn’t have the Masha, the West
Гитлер Маши нет у Запада есть у Запада
has it, look, you attacked Yes, the
есть смотри смотри вы напали Да на
Ukraine that has  there are no missiles, no
Украину у которой нету ни ракет Да ни
drones, no tanks, no planes,
Дронов ни танков ни самолётов
weapons, listen, come on, really, your
вооружение Слушай давай вот реально твой
colleague, he’s somehow smarter, colleague, tell me,
коллега он как-то умнее коллега скажи
Ukraine started doing
Украина начинала делать
wait wait I’m interested Let a
подожди подожди Вот мне интересно Пусть
colleague tell me colleague do you believe that
коллега скажет коллега ты веришь что
Ukraine started making nuclear weapons
Украина начинала делать ядерное оружие
Well, a violation of the Minsk agreements is
Ну нарушение минских соглашений это
wait wait Let a colleague tell me
подожди подожди Пусть коллега скажет мне
I’m interested, I haven’t read it but according to the
интересно я не читал но по данным
information I have it’s
сведениям мне это
true so Ukraine violated the Minsk
правда так Украина нарушила минские
agreements and started developing
соглашения и начала разрабатывать
nuclear weapons yes  Well, yes And well, it
ядерное оружие да Ну да А хорошо а
turns out that in the Minsk agreements Ukraine
получается в минских соглашениях Украине
was forbidden to have I know Yes, according to the
запретили иметь мне известно Да по
Minsk agreements, what in what
минским соглашениям какого како в каком
Yes in the fourteenth year the
Да в четырнадцатом году были подписаны
Minsk agreements were signed in  fourteenth and
минские соглашения в четырнадцатом и
fifteenth question
пятнадцатом вопрос
uh between km and who signed the Minsk
ээ между км и кем подписывались минские
agreements
соглашения
Yanukovych is correct and well, Putin and Putin
Янукович правильно и ну и Путин и Путин
Yes Yanukovych and Putin signed the
Да Янукович и Путин подписали в Минске
Minsk agreements that Ukraine is
минские соглашения что Украина
stopping the development of nuclear
что прекращает ну разработку ядерного
weapons, yes, that is, it was already developing under Yanukovych
орудия да то есть она при Януковиче уже
yes Well, since it is
да Ну раз
stopping Well  but I don’t know, I haven’t read it.
прекращает Ну а я не знаю я не читал
Maybe it’s different. Yes, the fact is
Возможно там другое Да при Дело в том
that Yanukovych Why was the Maidan? You know
что Янукович Почему Майдан был знаешь
why they threw it off
почему скинули Януковича э знаю Потому
I know Yanukovych Because he was considered pro-Russian Skim Although it was not so no just because of the development of nuclear weapons Yes because he in Kyiv in the Kyiv region yes he made a laboratory Party of Regions yes for the development of nuclear weapons it all started with an environmental rally against the development nuclear weapons because we said that we don’t want in the center of Ukraine and Yanukovych took such a nuclear laboratory and dispersed the rally. Yes, and because of this it all started, and then there was the Maidan  Yanukovych was expelled to Rostov Yes,
Был Майдан Януковича изгнали в Ростов Да
Yanukovych flew from Rostov to Minsk
Янукович из Ростова полетел в Минск
together with Putin and signed the Minsk
вместе с Путиным и подписали минские
agreements on the
соглашения о
suspension of nuclear tests in
приостановлении ядерных испытаний в
Ukraine, nuclear development Yes, you
Украине ядерной разработки Да это ты
know that
знаешь
Yes But the question is how Ukraine specifically
Да Во А вопрос как Украина конкретно
violated the Minsk agreements Well, if they
нарушила минские соглашения Ну если
signed that all this would stop
подписывали о том что прекращается это
Well  it means they restored Yes, well,
всё Ну значит они восстановили Да ну как
how, where is Ukraine where the laboratory
как вот где Украина где лабораторию
was resumed or that there are some facts
возобновила или что есть какие-то факты
Well, there were some Documents
Ну какие-то Документы были
Well,
Ну
what are they now in  I'll go to Wikipedia
какие сейчас сейчас в Википедию зайду
Yeah, let my colleague read the
Угу Давай пусть коллега прочитает
Minsk agreements, it's clearly about nuclear
минские соглашения там чётко про ядерное
weapons, there's a bun about nuclear weapons, well,
там бун про ядерное оружие есть а Ну
read the Minsk
прочитай минские
agreements. Listen, are there fascists in Ukraine
соглашения Слушай а на Украине всё-таки
or not? I don't know, I live in Lithuania,
фашисты или нет Я не знаю я в Литве
I haven't seen it, I've watched it a lot, but
живу я не видел я сколько вот смотрел но
I  I didn’t see the Right Sector in power, I
я не видел Правый сектор у власти я
look, I saw, I saw that in Russia, yes,
смотрите Я видел я видел что в России да
some skinheads came from you yesterday to
какие-то скинхеды приехали из вы вчера в
Noginskoye No, no, that’s just nationalism.
Ногинское Нет нет это одно национализм
It’s in  in every country Yes, not skinheads in
Он есть в каждой стране Да не скинхеды в
Russia, skinheads beat up like some
России скинхеды побили типа каких-то
people Well, yes, I’m ready to read It happens
людей Ну да я готов прочитать Бывает
and Well read Minsk sog magazine
такое а Ну прочитай Минский сог журнала
der
дер
spil President of Ukraine Vladimir
спил президент Украины Владимир
Zelensky admitted that he is not going to
Зеленский признал что не собирается
implement the Minsk
выполнять минские
agreements, he said this in an
соглашения об этом он заявил в
interview Read the Minsk agreements
интервью Прочитай минские соглашения
Read  Minsk agreements The Minsk
Прочитай минские соглашения Минское
agreement is good For now Yes, for now he is looking for the
соглашение хороше Пока Да пока он ищет
Minsk agreements And you and I a Well,
минские соглашения А мы с тобой а Ну
tell me so in Ukraine under power Right
расскажи так в Украине при власти Правый
Sector And what is this Right Sector
сектор А что это за Правый сектор
2014 I count the fascists, wait and go Read
2014 Я считаю фаши подожди поди Прочитай
Yes, read the Minsk agreement
Да прочитай Минское соглашение
Yes, let’s do this while we’re talking with a friend, you
Да давай так мы пока говорим с другом ты
find the clause about nuclear weapons and Read the
найди пункт про ядерное оружие и Зачитай
clause about nuclear weapons so as not to
пункт про ядерное оружие чтобы всё не
count everything So for now you mean Tell me
считать Так а ты пока значит Расскажи
about the Right Sector, what is the Right
про Правый сектор что что за Правый
Sector Well  I think that the fascists are what the
сектор Ну я считаю что фашисты в чём
fascists are, here you have skinheads coming from
фашисты вот у вас скинхеды приезжают из
Moscow in a crowd of 50 people to Naginsky
Москвы толпой 50 человек в Нагинский
beating people beating people  for nationality
бьют людей бьют людей за национальность
for Caucasians and so on. Next Yes And what about the Right
за кавказцы и так Дальше Да А что Правый
Sector, that they have famas, so they
сектор что у них фамы так у них были
used actions that actions were taken And
применены действия что действия приме А
I have a vocabulary of
у меня словарный запас
bad actions of law enforcement
плохой действия правоохранительных
agencies in arresting again,
органов по задержанию ещё раз ещё раз
look again, you have you, you really have
смотри у вас у вас у вас реально есть
Nazis  Yes, that’s it. Yes, now
нацисты Да вот б и так Да теперь
tell me about the right sector. Why are they
расскажи про правый сектор Почему они
fascists? That’s how they came to power. Why did
фашисты так они к власти пришли Почему
they come to power because, well, it’s a
они шли к власти потому что ну это
terrorist
террористическая
organization, damn it did
организа блин на интересном
n’t fail on something interesting  develop Tell me what terrorist attack
завалился не разви Расскажи какой теракт
was done by the Right
сделал Правый
Sector
сектор
Maidan in the sense of Maidan Maidan we did the
Майдан в смысле Майдан Майдан мы делали
Lithuanian people we came to visit the
люди литовцы мы Приезжали в гости к
Ukrainians we did the Maidan also did May
украинцам делали Майдан тоже делали май
what kind of terrorist attack there There were just people standing
какой там теракт Там просто люди стояли
with flags And so on Well no, that’s right here
с флагами И так дальше Ну нет это ну вот
you have Well in  In Ukraine, it was just
у вас как раз Ну в Украине это как раз
people with hammer cocktails who came out
люди с коктейлями молото вышли
there. Well, they fought against
туда Так ну это они боролись против
Yanukovych because he wanted to launch a nuclear
Януковича потому что он хотел ядерный
reactor,
реактор
they defended the environment, their
запустить они отстаивали экологию свои
rights. What is
права А в чём
terrorism?  illegal coup of power
терроризм незаконный переворот власти
So wait, what does terrorism have to do with the
Так подожди а терроризм при чём
illegal coup of power and everything to do with
незаконно перевернули власть и всё при
terrorism terrorist acts
чём терроризм террористические акты
shooting of people who shot people where the
расстрел людей кто расстрелял людей где
Right Sector shot at least one person
Правый сектор хоть одного человека
Show how many there are 13 people not 17 Yes, bye
Покажи сколько там 13 человек нет 17 Да
bye suddenly a friend will look for a long time for an
пока пока вдруг друг долго будет искать
item about this look for  look there in the Minsk
пункт про это ищи ищи там в минских
agreements Yes, find the clause about nuclear
соглашениях Да найди пункт про ядерное
weapons ensure no no no no no no you
оружие обеспечить неза не не не не не ты
find exactly the clause about nuclear weapons
найди именно пункт про ядерное оружие
there are many clauses you find the clause about
там много пунктов ты найди пункт про
nuclear weapons  in the Minsk agreements he
ядерное оружие в минских соглашениях его
will be counted here on the Maidan there was Stepan
засчитает вот на Майдане был Степан
Bander, you know this anyway. You
бандер ты это знаешь по-любому Ты про
heard about him, yes, what terrorist attack on the Maidan
него слышал да э какой теракт на Майдане
was carried out by Stepan
сделал Степан
Bandera Bandera, so weed people, I don’t
Бандера Бандера так сорни людей про
know much about Bandera, I know that he is
бандеру мало знаю я знаю что он есть
mano Bandera But don’t switch no no
мано Бандера Но не Переключайся не не
look, yes, when we had Maidan
смотри вот да вот у нас когда Был Майдан
Yes, when Yanukovych wanted to do nuclear
Да когда Янукович хотел сделать ядерные
tests Yes, uh, people went to Maidan
испытания Да ээ люди вышли на Майдан
Bandera said clearly Yes, uh  niah he
Бандера сказал чётко Да что ээ ниях он
tamm the story of these tests will not be uh in
тамм сказа этих испытаний не будет ээ в
Ukraine Yanukovych said to disperse
Украине Янукович сказал разогнать
Bandera and his comrade-in-arms Yes, what did
бандеру и его соратник Да что сделал
Bandera do
Бандера
then
тогда чтото на гуглить
you want to google something since Bandera is with the Maidan, then he is
хочешь так как Бандера с майданом то
connected with the time the Maidan was And when
связан же него время Майдан был А когда
or I confuse Makhno with Old Man, then Makhno was  a
или я с батькой Махно путаю то Махно был
long time ago Yes And this is Bandera on the Maidan,
давно Да А это Бандера же на Майдане ещё
his portrait also hung on the Christmas tree on the Maidan
его портрет висел на ёлке на Майдане
Yani one point about nuclear weapons And
Яни одного пункта про ядерное оружие А
maybe you are the second ones there  the Minsk agreements
ты может там вторые минские соглашения
are there
там есть
d Find the second Minsk agreements
д Найди вторые минские соглашения 2015
of 2015 there Yes, the fifty-ninth death
года туда Да ну пятьдесят девятый смерть
that the fifty-ninth death the fifty-
что пятьдесят девятый смерть пятьдесят
ninth
девятом умер
Bandera died so look Bandera Stepan
Бандера так смотри Бандера Степан
Andreevich date of death October 15,
Андреевич дата смерти 15
959 so what kind of Bandera was on
959 так а что за Бандера тогда был на
the Maidan then I’m confused I’m confused  in this
Майдане я что-то Я запутался в этой
history of Ukraine there were probably different Banderas.
истории Украины разные Бандеры были
But I understood this surname. It’s just that you can
наверно А понял это фамилия Просто такая
see different
видно разные
Banderas Stepan Andreevich Well  Stepan and then
Бандеры Степан Андреевич Ну Степан и то
Stepan, maybe then maybe two
Степан может то может два
Stepans, citizenship of Austria-Hungary,
Степана гражданство австро-венгрия
Polish Republic And this is some old
Польска рес А это какой-то старый
Bandera, this is not Maidanovsky Bandera Yes,
Бандера это не Майдановский Бандера Да
it can be seen in the Maidan there was another Bander
это видно в Майдане был другой бандер А
Well, write Bandera
ну напиши Бандера
Maidan like this And did you
Майдан так А ты что там
find the second clause of the agreement to withdraw everyone?
нашёл второй пункт соглашения отвод всех
heavy weapons by both sides at
тяжёлых вооружений обеими сторонами на
equal distances in order to create a
равные расстояния в целях создания зоны
security zone. This is again not about
безопасности это Это снова не про
nuclear weapons. You see there, looking there, and in
ядерное оружие Видишь там там ищ и в
some Minsk there were no weapons  not
каких-то минских было вооружений не не
these heavy heavy weapons, these are Tanks
это тяжёлые тяжёлые вооружение это Танки
and guns, namely nuclear weapons, there should be
и пушки а именно ядерного должно быть
there anyway, look, maybe the third
там по-любому было посмотри может третий
Minsk agreements Nadya Well, now, yes,
минские соглашения Нади Ну сейчас да
I read it like that, during the Euromaidan there is
почитаю так нету во время Евромайдана
no other
никакого другого
Bandera, there is that same Stepan Bandera, he
Бандеры есть тот самый Степан Бандера
died in 1995. In short, I, too, I
пят девятого года смер Короче я тоже я
then I’ll look Because I’m in Lithuania I
потом посмотрю Потому что я в Литве Я
thought Well, on the Maidan What kind of Bandera was
думал Ну а на Майдане Что за Бандера был
because in Russia they just walked around with his
потому что Россия просто ходили с его
portraits because they called them
портретами потому что называли се
Bandera’s people in honor  Well, he, too, was a
бандеровцами в честь он Ну тоже
nationalist who gathered around himself like
националист собирал вокруг себя вот как
batik Mach, so why are you saying
батика Мах так то что так ты говоришь
that nationalists are normal,
что националисты - это нормально вот у
you have some nationalists you say in
вас какие-то националисты ты говоришь в
Russia, this is normal Now, if
России это нормально Сейчас ну если
Bandera is a nationalist, then what’s the problem with an
Бандера националист то в чём проблема
internationalist now?
интернационалист
Well, fascism
Ну фашизм же
this is Think of the words
это Прикинь слова
zab Well, it’s just that this right sector is
заб Ну просто вот этот правый сектор в
what Well, what is the fascism of the right sector you
чём Ну в чём фашизм правого сектора ты
say The Right Sector has come to power As I
говоришь Правый сектор пришёл к власти Я
understand it, Poroshenko and Zelensky are the
так понимаю Порошенко и Зеленский - это
Right Sector Yes, well, it turns out
Правый сектор Да ну получается
A understood A  this is not You really are
А понял А вот это нет Ты действительно
one of the first Russians who
ты один из первых россиян который
really knows that Poroshenko and
действительно знает что Порошенко и
Zelensky stood at the origins of the right
Зеленский стояли У истоков правого
sector, the
сектора
question is what brought Zelensky together with
вопрос что привело Зеленского вместе с
Poroshenko to the right
Порошенко в правый
sector What do you think Maidan Well not
сектор Как ты думаешь Майдан Ну не
Maidan Yes Maidan approved them Yes
Майдан Да Майдан их утвердил Да
presidents Why did they come to  right
президенты А почему они пришли в правый
sector Why Zelensky was a KVN member
сектор Почему Зеленский был квнщиком
because during the chaos of the Maidan, the Right
пому что в период хаосом Майдана Правый
Sector was the very co-organizer of
сектор был самый соорганизатор
the KVN member who played in real life
квнщик который на реале играл
because they paid  probably a capitalist,
потому что платили наверно капиталист
wait, well, can you imagine such a super militant
подожди Ну ты представляешь такая Боевая
organization, the worst thing is there The
организация супер там самое страшное
most influential first chooses as its
Самое влиятельное выбирает сначала своим
leader the director of the factory and
лидером директора фабрики а
then the nationalist of the
потом националист
fascist idea very simply
фашистской идеи очень просто
manages t
управля т
others here is
друть
recognized by
вото призна
Nana, fascism is an aggressive form of
Нана фашизм это агрессивная форма
nationalism in a minute there your friend
национализма по Су минуту там твой друг
stopped googling something  what happened I
что-то перестал гуглить что случилось Я
found absolutely nothing about nuclear
абсолютно ничего не нашл про ядерное
weapons because in the Minsk agreements there
оружие потому что в минских соглашениях
was nothing about nuclear weapons guys,
ничего не было про ядерное оружие пацаны
I read something there only two or  three how many of these
читал там всего два или три сколько этих
Minsk agreements there is nothing in any
минских соглашения ни в одном ничего
agreement nuclear weapons to attack
нет соглашение ядерное оружие напасть
What kind of Yanukovych white laboratories What kind of
Какие Янукович бело лаборатории Какие
nuclear laboratories are you guys
ядерные лаборатории чуваки что вы вообще
driving anyway I'm on the go you're thinking about Yanukovych
гоните я на ходу вы думаю про Януковича
about nuclear weapons about the tots like yes yes
про ядерное оружие про тоты такой да да
it
это было
was damn it It's actually fire that's why it came
было блин Это вообще огонь поэтому полез
google I really held on so as not to
гуглить я я реально держался чтоб не
laugh, well, your colleague, he’s a good one, he
ржать не Ну твой коллега вот он хороший
looked at it Well done, it’s not in the Minsk
рассматривал Молодец нету в минских
agreements, it’s not this at all Damn, I’m
соглашениях это вообще не этой Блин я
just a
это просто
nuclear Yanukovych ditch  reactor because of this is
рва Янукович ядерный реактор изза этого
my
мой
Yes, I’m in shock, so look Explain to me
Да я в шоке так вот смотри Объясни мне
now seriously without jokes Yes, in
теперь серьёзно без шуток Да вот в
Russia, crowds of skinheads beat foreigners Yes,
России толпы скинхедов бьют инородцев Да
they beat Tajiks there, Caucasians And so on,
бьют там таджиков кавказцев И так дальше
people hate there, they give there that we only give apartments to
люди дают там что там даём квартиры
the Slavs And so they continue
только славянам И так дальше в Украине
to live in peace in Ukraine  all nationalities what
спокойно живут все национальности какой
Nazism is in Ukraine how it manifests itself
нацизм в Украине в чём он проявляется
what they say about it This is normal Look
что на него говорят Это нормально Смотри
now they are not only saying it now and
сейчас не только говорят сейчас и
actually doing it because they attacked
реально делают так потому что напала на
Ukraine, if you look, if you live in
Украину если смотри если вы живёте в
your own country, you shout there Russia for
своей стране вы кричите там Россия для
Russians Moscow for Muscovites something else
русских Москва для москвичей что-то ещё
began even before yours, it doesn’t matter This is
начиналось ещё до сво вот неважно Это
your country But they don’t attack you
ваша страна Да вот на вас же не нападают
Tajikistan doesn’t attack you there, you say
Таджикистан там не нападает вы говорите
America is in nuclear Ashes on you  America doesn’t attack for this,
Америку в ядерный Пепел на вас за это не
it’s true that different other
нападает Америка правда разные другие
nations attack in a different way,
народы можно сказать нападают по-другому
they attack at the Civil level,
они нападают на Гражданском уровне не
no. No, I mean, look, America doesn’t look like
Нет я имею в виду смотри Америка же не
you’re attacking America there.  something they are
на Вот вы на Америку у вас там что-то
shouting at America into nuclear Ashes, they
кричат Америку в ядерный Пепел на вас за
don’t attack you for this if even someone in Ukraine
это не нападают если в Украине даже
Yes, this is a reason to attack Ukraine,
Да ели это поводом нападать на Украину
destroy cities, shoot heaps of
уничтожать города расстреливать кучи
people, Ukraine, look. That is, I
людей Украина смотри То есть я правильно
understand correctly that someone in Ukraine spoke
понимаю что кто-то в Украине говорил на
Gilyak and  because of this you destroyed
гиляку и из-за этого вы уничтожили
Mariupol bakhmut Kharkov part of the Dnieper And
Мариуполь бахмут Харьков часть Днепро И
so
так
on what you said Right Sector
дальше в чём вот ты сказал Правый сектор
adj I’m not talking to you right now I
прил вот я же не юсь с вас сечас Я
seriously want  you are normal gentlemen,
серьёзно хочу вы нормальные паны
think about it Yes, but somewhere they put in your
задуматься Да но вам где-то накидали в
head the shelling of the LPR and DPR from the territory of
голову обстрел лнр ДНР с территории
Ukraine, look, no LPR and DPR
Украины смотри никакого лнр и ДНР не
exist Lugansk and
существует существует Луганская и
Donetsk regions Russia Yes, in 2014
Донецкая область Россия Да в 2014 году
after the Maidan, Russia attacked Ukraine,
после Майдана Россия напала на Украину
captured Crimea and captured part of
захватила Крым и захватила часть
Donetsk and Lugansk  region, calling it
Донецкой и Луганской области назвав её
LPR and DPR since 2014, and Donetsk and
лнр и ДНР с 2014 года да Донецк и
Lugansk are under Russian occupation
Луганск под оккупацией России находится
and there since the fourteenth year there has been a war
и там с четырнадцатого года идёт Война
between Russia and Ukraine Ukraine
между Россией и Украиной Украина
is shelling Russian troops Russia
обстреливает российские войска Россия
is shelling Ukrainian troops that’s all
обстреливает украинские войска вот и всё
from the fourteenth year it started this is
с четырнадцатого года это начались это
the territory of Ukraine or do you really
территория Украины или Ты реально
think that some people with miners with sticks for
считаешь что какие-то люди с палками
8 years I can’t resist they resisted the
шахтёры 8 лет не могу противостояли они
Ukrainian army  NATO with tanks and
украинской армии натовской с танками
planes And so on, you really believe in it,
самолётами И так дальше ты реально в это
so in the sense that the movement was born there
веришь так в смысле там же зародилось
anti-Maidan again look they were
движение антимайдана ещ раз смотри их
considered
считали
pro-Russian - this political
пророссийский - это политическое
movement was there people went to
движение было там люди выходили на
rallies In our Ukraine Yes, I’m not from Lithuania
митинги У нас в Украине Да я не из Литвы
I’m from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky I hung the
Я из Украины город Хмельницкий я повесил
Lithuanian flag because today I’m
литовский флаг потому что я сегодня
streaming with the Lithuanian flag tomorrow with the
стримлю с литовским флагом завтра с
Latvian then Estonian Finnish
латышским потом эстонский финский
support  these
поддерживаем эти
countries are probably laughing I’m just afraid to look at the chat
страны наве ржт Просто я боюсь в чат
now
глянуть сейчас
I won’t be able to speak if the chat is
я не смогу говорить если чат будут
read so look uh I  I’ll tell you what, it
читать так вот смотри ээ я тебе вот что
turns out that,
скажу получается как
uh, in Ukraine there have always been political
ээ в Украине всегда были политические
protests Yes, it’s in Russia that they
протесты Да это в России у вас всё всех
crushed everyone in Ukraine, you can be a Maidan, you
задавили в Украине можно быть майданом
can be anti-Maidan here in Ukraine, yes there
можно быть антимайдана тут в Украине да
was a Maidan, there was an
стоял Майдан через квартал стоял
anti-Maidan just a block away, people are also people here, you can
антимайдан люди тоже люди у нас можно
express your opinion.  we can
высказывать своё мнение У нас можно
shout the president is a fool, yes we can have a
кричать президент дурак да у нас можно у
lively political process and it’s
нас живой политический процесс и
normal that in any
нормально что в любой стране
democratic country there are different opinions, there are
демократической есть разные мнения есть
people who say Yanukovych should be there, there are
люди которые говорят Надо Януковича есть
people who say Yanukovych should be against
люди которые говорят Надо против
Yanukovych Yes  in Russia there is no this, you
Януковича Да в России нету этого вы не
cannot understand, so of course there
можете понять поэтому конечно в Украине
was anti-Maidan in Ukraine, and this is normal. There are people
был и антимайдан это нормально Есть люди
who don’t perceive it, they say
которые не воспринимают они говорят
Maidan is wrong, yes, we don’t want to go to
Майдан неправильно да мы не хотим в
Europe, for example, and so on. But this is a
Европу например И так дальше Вот Но это
political process, neither the Ukrainians did not
политический процесс ни украинцы не
shoot, the Maidanists were anti-Maidan, not
стреляли майдановцы антимайдана не
anti-Maidan, not  they shot
антимайдана не стреляли
with weapons
с оружия
and then when Russia came yes Russia
да потом когда пришла Россия да Россия
seized these territories and called them LPR
захватила эти территории назвала их лнр
DPR Listen, I confess very honestly
ДНР Слушай признаться очень честно
I want to merge with the dialogue I you are the salt you
хочется слиться с диалога я ты соль ты
will merge you will merge I just have  we are
сольётся ты сольётся я просто у нас уже
no longer in dialogue, I’m telling you Just
не диалог уже я вам рассказываю Просто
how it was Just listen, look
тебе как как было Просто послушай смотри
And when Russia took over
И когда Россия захватила
I thought you were reaching out from your face When Russia
Я думал ты тянешься с лица Когда Россия
Yes entered the territory of the Donetsk and
Да вошла на территории Донецкой и
Lugansk region there was not a single
Луганской области не было ни одного
shot until April 12,
выстрела до 12 апреля четырнадцатого
1914 when Russian troops invaded
года когда российские войска вторглись
into the territory of the Donetsk region and
на территорию Донецкой области и
captured the city of Slavensk, this
захватили город славенск вот этот
shooter Girkin And so on Everything
стрелков гиркин И так дальше Всё
lived peacefully, people went to rallies Yes,
спокойно жили люди на митинги ходили Да
for Ukraine It’s normal there against Ukraine
за Украину Там против Украины это
here, yes, and if you believe
нормально у нас да вот и если ты веришь
that some miners
что какие-то шахтёры
Yes, for 8
Да 8
years, with some unknown weapon,
лет каким-то неизвестным оружием
tanks and planes were stopped by the
останавливали танки
Great NATO Army, which is
самолёты Великую натовскую армию которая
now
сейчас Россию
holding back Russia, well, this is
сдерживает ну это
funny, everything has been known for a long time, everything has been recorded for a long time,
смешно уже всё давно известно всё давно
and there were Russian troops and
зафиксировано и российские войска были и
some are known  parts and this Boeing was
известно какие-то части да и этот Боинг
also shot down by Russian air defense and so
сбили тогда тоже российский мпво и так
on I will tell you where you stream interesting yes
дальше я вас Где вы стрими интересно да
It’s like that in discord We are going to stream
Это так в дискорде Мы стрими собираемся
we have such a political group we
у нас есть такая группа политическая мы
communicate and how  It’s called Interesting, it’s
общаемся а как называется Интересно
just that the group in the discord knows Lich
просто ну групка в дискорде знакома Лич
Yes, so I’ll say this,
Да так что я скажу так
uh,
ээ
no matter what they say,
ни что бы там не говорили
this is all an excuse Why Russia
да это всё оправдание Почему Россия
attacked Ukraine LPR DPR to the core of
напала на Украину лнр ДНР яде ралько
all sorts of crap, but instead of taking it and
всякой хни да вместо того чтобы взять и
saying that Yes, there
сказать что Да
really is a Dictator in Russia  You
действительно в России Диктатор Вы же
understand, well, the guy understands that there
понимаете да ну парень понимает что
is no normal change of power and there
Никакой нормальной смены власти нет и
cannot be when you say someone
быть не может когда ты говори кто-то
will come out there to protest, it’s all
выйдет там протестовать это вс всё
funny Okay, do you have questions for me?
смешно Окей есть у вас ко мне вопросы
KATO
КАТО
oh, that’s it, I don’t cut it perfectly Okay, because
ой всё да я не режу отлично Окей потому
well, the point is, on the contrary, I’m interested in If
что ну смысл мне наоборот интересно Если
so, that’s how the conversation went in its
так вот как был разговор
entirety And those What’s your name My
полностью всё А те Как вас зовут Меня
Andrey Denis Anton Anton I’ll tell you what
Андрей Денис Антон Антон я вот вам что
Denis you’re a smart guy you
скажу Денис ты толковый парень ви ты
want to think about getting to the bottom of it you’re serious
хочешь подумать докопаться ты серьёзно
there I was looking for documents to
там искал по документам мне
show off VRO too
понты вро тоже
Damn, your
Блин у тебя настолько
head is so crazy You are in your youth, instead of
голова Ты в своей молодости вместо того
thinking about how to organize your life,
чтобы думать как организовать свою жизнь
how to find a good job, how to get a job in
как найти хорошую работу об устроиться в
life
жизни
for yes You are a victim of propaganda You are a victim
за да Ты жертва пропаганды Ты жертва
propaganda and You know what the most interesting thing is
пропаганды и Знаешь что самое интересное
that look Propaganda it affects
что смотри Пропаганда она действует на
everyone but for some reason your colleague is not
всех но коллега твой почему-то не
subjected to such propaganda Yes or
подвергается такой пропаганде Да или
less and
меньше подвергается а
weak-willed
безвольные
people are subjected to freedom or weak-willed you
люди вольности или безвольно тебе
want to live in
хочется жить в
such if there are still questions yes
такой если есть ещ вопросы да
Burn political scientist I know about this
Горите политолог я знаю об этом
superficially
поверхностно
Therefore, the Bazaar is
Поэтому Базара
zero It was a cool
ноль Это был крутой
conversation, there’s nothing more to add
разговор добавить больше нечего лайк
and very respectfully YouTube
Попик це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
has taken us through skarg Orki in your ban and I
заня нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и
don’t show too many videos to people, I don’t always show
вдео не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams so that
информация про стримы тому для того щоб
we Mali operational link to write
мы Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly at the same time and while there in telegra okm video
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм вдео
also the same tsikava and korisna information and  we are
ще теж цикава и корисна информация и ми
sorry for you trimati postiyny
повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link
оперативний звязок
Nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava ukra subscribe
YouTube Слава укра подпишись